

# **APARNA SUBEDI**



## Canada | +1 (437) 660-5991 | aparna.subedi@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary**

An experienced professional with 4+ years of experience in **2D-3D animation** with strong background in **game design and film production pipeline**. Expert in developing **high quality characters**, **environments**, **and gaming assets**. Experienced in polygonal modeling, UV mapping, texturing, hand painted PBR, lighting both for hard and soft surface models. Working knowledge of **2D**, **3D**, **motion graphics**, **composition**, **VR**, **and photogrammetry**.

#### Key skills

<b>Modelling Software</b>	3D Maya, Max, ZBrush, Speedtree, Blender
Texturing Software	Substance painter, Mari, Keyshot
Rendering Engine	Marmoset, Vray, Redshift, Arnold, Mental ray
VFX and Compositing	Adobe Premiere Pro, After Effects, Nuke
Other Software	Unreal, Unity, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator

#### **Professional Experience**

### Animator/Graphic Designer, Freelancer (Client: VND USA, VND Canada, YouTube)

Oct 2021 - Present

- Developed graphics content: e-cards, posters, flyers etc. for VND to help promote their mediation events, classes etc. resulting in an increase of sign-ups by 50%.
- Designed VND's promotional graphic content for Vitality Magazine, Canada's largest publications on natural health.
- Created animation videos; background for their internal workshops, promotions to educate regarding meditation.
- Designed 2D characters for kids' rhyme: conducted research, incorporated cultural elements, traditional clothing, accessories to help introduce kids to vibrant traditions and heritage of Nepal.
- Developed storyboarding, mood boards, backgrounds to display iconic landmarks, landscapes, mountains of Nepal.
- Animated characters to rhythm, resulting in increased engagement and cultural connection.

### Lead Motion Graphics Artist, Innovate Nepal Group – Kathmandu, Nepal

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

- Led team of 30+ in development of the animation content: academic videos, promotional videos etc.
- Contributed to successful development of two large-scale educational applications (My Second Teacher) for Govt. of Nepal and Singapore to digitize their educational system. The app was awarded "Best e-learning app" in Asia in 2020.
- Introduced innovative features and user-centric design, offering a convenient and engaging platform for students.
- Developed interactive academic videos, mock tests for A- level, IGCSE students resulting in improved grades by 81%.
- Collaborated with content creators, and subject matter experts to conceptualize, storyboard, and develop motion graphics content ensuring the alignment of project goals, deadlines, specifications, target audience.
- Developed new custom pipelines which improved workflow productivity and reduced bottlenecks by 70%.
- Provided training and mentorship to junior artists to help improve skills and encourage continuous learning.
- Conducted quality assurance checks on motion graphics content to ensure accuracy, consistency, adherence to brand guidelines and technical specifications.

### Motion Graphics Artist, Innovate Nepal Group – Kathmandu, Nepal

Sep 2018 – Sep 2019

- Produced high quality animation, visuals, interactive animations with diagrams, charts, typography, illustrations, sound effects to enhance understanding and retention of the academic content.
- Engaged with managers to gather requirements, set objectives, tasks, deadlines, deliverables of various projects.
- Removed green screen, fine-tuned the keying settings, used techniques like rotoscoping to achieve realistic results in visual storytelling and compositing.

## **3D Animator,** Method studio – Aukland, New Zealand

Aug 2017 - May 2018

- Worked on a project to animate the bird with movements such as flapping, gliding, hovering, flying etc.
- Researched diverse types of bird movements to understand and incorporate the mechanics of bird in the animation.
- Constructed Controllers and IKs to produce bird animation, control the position and orientation of bird anatomy.

# **Education**

Graduate Diploma in **Creative technologies** - Advanced 3D, Media Design School, New Zealand Graduate Certificate in **3D Maya** - Maya Academy of Advanced Cinematics, India Bachelor of Science - Animation, Mahatma Gandhi University, India

Jun 2017 Oct 2015

**Dec 2014**